♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ In somewhere in
time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson and
his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in a nasty place ♪
♪ They try to survive
the wrath of Pearl ♪
♪ Just an evil gal who
wants to rule the world ♪
♪ From her castle below
she sets her sites above ♪
♪ Just to torture all
the captives on the
satellite of love ♪
♪ Get me down ♪
♪ I'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst I can find ♪
♪ La-La-La ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And I'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La-La-La ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La-La-La ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call
Cambot you're on ♪
♪ Gypsy star ♪
♪ Tom Tom check me out ♪
♪ Croooow I'm different ♪
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breaths ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La-La-La ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" ♪
(metal doors closing)
- Hi everyone welcome
to the cub den of love.
- Hi.
- We're just having
our den meeting.
- Bobcats, do or die!
- Ah, Croooow, why
don't you tell them
what we've done so far.
- Well, we worked
on then gave up on
our pinewood derby car,
finished the pipe cleaner owl,
crafted a macaroni replica
of Van Gogh's self portrait
with bandaged ear and we
sang a song about trees.
- Right, and hey where's
Tom for all of this anyway?
- Present.
- Ooh. (laughs)
Tom, I don't quite no how
to tell you this but--
- You're a Brownie, Tom.
- I know I'm a Brownie,
I'm not stupid, you know.
- Well, Brownie
doesn't really work
with the whole cub
scout idiom, does it?
- Yeah, I think it's illegal.
- Look, you try
wearing little shorts
over a hoverskirt, I
got a great deal on this
at Value Village and besides
it's quite freeing. (laughs)
Now are we gonna eat cupcakes
and play mall ball or what?
- We'll be right back.
- Just think of
me as a shebelow.
- Um, no.
(upbeat music)
- And nice use of
ziti for the hat,
I think that gives it a real--
- Ah, now what the hell are you?
- Hey back off, okay, it's my
Flemish glass blower costume!
I bought it, I wanted to
get some use out of it!
- Take it easy.
- I grabbed it out of
the bin, it was on sale.
What, you'd rather I'd grab
the Spanish cortizon get up?
- Pearl's calling.
- I mean come on!
- Hello, Mike, Croooow,
Flemish glass blower.
In my quest to become a fully
accredited mad scientist,
I've overlooked some of
the simpler experiments
that got me interested
in mad scientist of the,
Brain Guy help me
out here, what?
- A madscientistologomy, a
madscientistabulinismary.
- Okay, yeah, yeah,
yeah, okay, right.
For instance you take a
potato, push a four inch piece
of zinc wire into one end, a
four inch piece of copper wire
into the other end, you
now have a crude battery.
Next, get your
assistant to cut power
to all the major
cities of the world.
- Cutting all power to New
York, London, Tokyo, Wonderland.
- Send your talking monkey
out to buy hundreds of tons
of potatoes, control the
world's supply of power
and soon you will
rule the universe.
It's that easy. (laughs evilly)
- I'm back.
- Yes, where are
they my precious?
- Oh, you wanted me to get
you something, didn't you?
- Oh, what--
- I was at the club
and I got distracted by
these delicious smoothies.
- Potatoes, you idiot, potatoes.
- Oh that's it, that's why
I got a potato smoothie.
- We're ruined, ruined,
unless, Mike, you're huge
and pink, you must have
potatoes around there.
- No, oh, you know what I
had one that I was saving
but it's pretty soft and
the eyes are all grown out.
- Eww, plus the one side
is all mushy and green.
- I don't care, Brain
Guy send it down quick.
Yes, triumph is mine,
this potato will power
the satellite link allowing
me to announce to the world--
- Eww, squishy.
- Oh nevermind.
Brain Guy, send him the movie,
"Boggy Creek II and
the Legend Continues."
- Right.
- Oh and you better
restore power
to all the world's capitals
and send them a note of
apology and a box of steaks.
- You know my smoothie
gives me great power.
- Oh, just hit yourself.
- Okay.
- Dear Boston, sorry about
cutting off the power,
please accept these box
of steaks as a recompense.
- Pearl, I've got
plenty of frozen okra.
- And rutabaga's
conduct electricity.
- Yeah.
- We're not gonna eat this
white hominy if you'd like that.
- Oh, movie time.
- Oh, we've got a movie.
(metal doors opening)
- [Tom] Didn't
want my okra, huh?
It's good okra.
And the legend continues
to be not heard about by anyone.
- [Crow] This is
rich man, poor man font.
- [Tom] You're right.
Pierced Chuck, $1.49 a pound.
- [Crow] From the Royal
Academy of Dramatic arts,
Jimmy Clem.
- [Tom] Really, there's too
much piercing in this movie.
- [Mike] Well that's
a half hearted attempt
at a porn name.
- [Crow] Don, Dan Atkins,
James Jeans Tennison.
- [Tom] Oh we were
with the Vanderburg's
in Charles and Pat and I decided
to make "The Legend
of Boggy Creek II."
- [Crow] Frank,
where's the music?
It should have it done
by the time it reaches
those dollar theaters.
(nighttime bugs calling)
- [Tom] That's Charles be
in over his head Pierce.
(slow music)
- [Mike] Yep, I'm up, I'm up.
- [Crow] Yeah that sun
has a hard time getting up
when we switch to
daylight savings time.
(slow beautiful music)
- [Narrator] The swamps
of southern Arkansas.
- [Tom] There's a legend
of a beer in these swamps.
- [Narrator] Stretching
out for miles and miles,
the beginning of a new day.
- [Mike] Full of thick,
southern promise.
- [Narrator] Been repeating
itself for centuries
upon centuries over
these bottomlands.
- [Crow] He said bottom.
(chuckles)
- [Narrator] Some of
these great Cyprus
have stood here before the
Vikings sailed the seas
in their long ships.
- [Tom] That was
like 1962, right?
- [Narrator] Towering above
this back water country
watching and listening to a
multitude of life, old and new.
- [Mike] This is the
story of fried pork rinds.
- [Narrator] It is here
that rivers are born
and creeks and
sleuths branch off
and cross this vast wilderness.
- [Crow] Good
for dumping poisons.
- [Narrator] They've
been dense thickets
and big timbers that rise up out
of this murky sun Earth.
- [Tom] We've been trying to
get a new NASCAR track in here.
(beautiful music)
- [Mike] Jim
Stafford's bath water.
- [Narrator] Beaver, mink,
birds, raccoons, snakes
and alligators are but
a few of the creatures
that make up the swamp's legend.
- [Crow] Mostly it's
worms and chiggers.
- [Narrator] Sometimes it's
eerie and sometimes pristine.
But it is ever alive and alert.
- [Mike] And it's got a
gun so don't try anything.
- [Narrator] The Sulfur
River makes it's way south
from here,
- Eww.
heading for the Mississippi
and then onto the saltwater
of the great gulf.
It is along this river
and it's tributaries
that decades ago
a legend was born.
- [Tom] But what
the hell is that?
- [Narrator] A legend that told
of a huge hairy
man-like creature
that lives and roams
these rivers and swamps.
- [Tom] But this, I
don't know what this is.
- [Narrator] It is said that
he stands over eight feet tall
and can weigh as
much as 300 pounds.
Thick hair covers
almost his entire body.
- [Crow] Although
he is thinning on top.
- [Tom] Oh, fur kills
man, that's right
it is hot today.
- [Narrator] It is
from this tributary
that the creature got it's name.
- [Mike] His name is tributary.
- [Narrator] This
is Boggy Creek.
(eerie music)
It branches off from the
river and makes it's way
through the swamp.
And the believability
of the sightings
along Boggy Creek
are rated very high.
- [Crow] By J.D. Power.
- [Narrator] But most of
them have been reported
by experienced
hunters and fishermen.
May there wade into this
back-watered country.
- [Tom] We will march
into the forbidden zone.
(animal growls)
- [Mike] So everyone
wants to know,
where the hell am
I going with this?
- [Narrator] Is it man?
- [Crow] I don't know, man.
- [Narrator] Could it be
a creature or is it myth?
- [Tom] How would I
know, spin, spin, spin.
- [Narrator] No
one really knows.
- [Mike] Look, I'm sorry
I even brought it up.
- [Narrator] So the
legend continues.
- [Crow] Oh boy, I'm not
continuing like I used to
when I was a kid,
let me tell you.
- [Tom] (hums) I'm gonna
wander into a suburb,
panic and crash through
a school window. (hums)
- [Mike] Come on, flower,
hand over the pollen,
that's right.
- [Crow] And another
thing about being a deer,
why do we have to cross
at the deer crossing sign?
- [Tom] Oh heck, I should
have brought my swim trunks.
(humming)
(birds call)
- [Narrator] Suddenly
flying low under the radar.
- [Mike] Two armed egrets.
- [Crow] There's
a zipper on his neck.
- [Mike] It's a gazelle
in a deer costume wow.
(dramatic music)
♪ It was the third
of December. ♪
- [Mike] It's hitching
a ride on the back
of a snapping turtle.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Ew, mucky
bottom, mucky bottom, ew.
- [Tom] Obviously this guy's
never gonna slaw on me,
can't even get out of the water.
(dramatic music)
(splash)
- [Crow] Ironically that
was Bambi's stepmother.
- [Tom] Honey, honey,
where'd you go honey,
honey, honey, honey?
- [Mike] (yawns) I'm just
gonna take a little nap.
- [Crow] Typical deer hunter.
- [Tom] Yeah and
meanwhile his wife's off
watching the Chippendales
with her girlfriends.
(eerie music)
- [Mike] It's okay, deer
spontaneously regenerate bodies.
- They're punting
the deer's head.
(crowd cheers)
(whistle blows)
- [Tom] They're
waving giant kibbles.
- [Mike] The cheerleaders
suggest that we go.
(crowd cheers)
- [Crow] I'm going the
cheerleader's plan is working.
- [Tom] Hey, a
bearded egg in a tie.
- [Mike] Black power.
- Come on, come on!
- [Crow] Nah, you take it.
(audience cheers)
- [Tom] They took our
advice and started winning.
- [Crow] We have
attached our egos to you.
(phone rings)
- [Mike] Wow, that antelope
has a lot of degrees.
- Oh yeah, hello, I mean
Dr. Lockhart's office.
- [Tom] Yes, I'm skinnier, yep.
- Yes sir.
He's at the game sir.
Get him, sir he's at the stadium
with 75,000 insane hog callers.
- [Crow] They're
calling insane hogs.
- Yes, sir, all
right, right away sir.
(crowd cheers)
- [Mike] The old halftime show.
Yo, yo mom, let me the
entire box of chello sweets.
- [Tom] I'm gonna leave
in the first quarter
to beat the rush.
- [Mike] There's a chickpea.
- [Crow] The
stadium is built next
to a giant Braun coffee grinder.
(audience cheers)
- [Mike] Sarah, Sarah,
your fly is open,
I saw it from across the field.
- [Tom] Just
resuscitate the patient,
I'll be there at the half.
- [Crow] Who's that skinny
guy who just talked to me?
- [Mike] Oh razorback hat
lacks the giant dignity
of the cheese wedge.
- [Tom] We welcome
accountants in section four.
- [Crow] Get your tongue
out of my ear, what are you.
- [Mike] I heard that.
(upbeat music)
- Yes, sir.
- [Tom] I'm ready
for some football.
- Listen we appreciate
you calling us.
We should be in Texarkana
before dark, yes.
Okay, thank you
very much goodbye.
All right, we got everything,
got the jeep, camper,
got the computer, mic censors.
- Everything but
the mic sensors.
- Okay, where's
your friend, Leslie?
- She should be here anytime.
- Tim, go ahead and get the
mic sensors, put them in.
- [Crow] Mike's right here.
- Got the.
(indistinct)
All right.
- Hi.
- [Tom] Keyboardist from "Fame."
- Anybody tell you
where we're going?
- Yep, Texarcana.
- [Crow] There's
a disco there right?
- Did they tell you we
were gonna be in the woods
most of the time?
- No, she said we're going
down looking for some kind
of wild man in the swamps.
- [Mike] I am that wild man.
- You just don't look like
you're dressed for the occasion.
- I got my jeans and shorts.
- [Crow] How will
they dress for the trip?
- I certainly hope so.
Load and up and let's go.
- [Mike] I'm Bocephus.
- [Brian] My name is
Brian C. Lockhart.
My friends call me Doc
and I'm a professor
of anthropology
at the University of Arkansas
located deep in the
Ozark Mountains.
- [Tom] I'm a dimwitted left.
- [Brian] With me one
of my freshman students,
Tim Thorne.
- [Crow] My
snap towel manager.
- [Brian] Leslie Walker,
all I know about her,
she's a good friend
of Tonya Yazzie
one of my pride students.
- [Tom] Pride students
in that she gets C's
but she's really cute.
(dramatic folk music)
- [Mike] We're going camping
and you're gonna watch.
- [Brian] After my call
from the Miller County
Sheriff's Department,
we were soon leaving
the rolling hills
of northern Arkansas behind,
headed for the swamps.
- [Tom] Hey the Tomb
of the unknown cracker.
(dramatic folk music)
- [Crow] Tim had a bladder
the size of a thimble.
- [Mike] Here's where the legend
worked the nightshift.
- [Tom] Even this place
has a great website.
- Can I help you all?
- [Crow] Yes, do you sell
turquoise plastic pit helmets?
- Good evening.
Do you you have any ammunition.
- Yes, sir.
- [Mike] We both
forgot our teeth.
- I need a box of 30 30 shells.
- Regular or hollow point?
- It doesn't matter.
- [Mike] Want this
on your Klan account?
- You all going camping?
- I guess you could say that.
We're looking for the
Boggy Creek creature.
- [Tom] I married her.
(laughs)
- There ain't no
such thing you know.
- [Crow] I know but
we got this funding.
- I guess that's why we're here,
we're gonna try to determine
if there is one or not.
- You can take my word for
it there ain't no monsters
around here.
- [Mike] Well do you
have any puffy hats
with filthy sayings?
- I believe that's
about all we need.
- Hey, boy, where do you
think you're gonna find
that monster?
- [Tom] Leave me alone you guys.
- I'm gonna find him in
the swamp if it exists.
- Bet he don't.
- He's been seen over 100
times since the early 50's.
- Seen by who drunks or
city folk like you all
wanting your name
in the newspaper.
- [Tom] Okay, call
off your dogs.
- What do I owe you?
- That'll be $16.59 please.
- [Mike] You wanna
contribute to our fund
for the war against
northern aggression?
- [Crow] So that's
money, usually we get paid
in possum hides.
- Thank you.
You know something, Will?
- [Mike] I don't
like your neck sweat.
- We oughta go down there
to that swamp tonight
with a monkey suit
and these here folks
would stay tommorrow night
at the motel in the city.
(laughs)
- [Tom] Well it ain't
gonna work now Earl,
he's standing right there.
(laughs)
- You know something, I believe
there's a creature here.
- [Tom] There is is.
- And being a city fella like
I am, I'm scared to death.
That's why I got a 30 30
rifle in the back of that jeep
and I bought this box of shells.
- [Tom] Liberal.
- In fact, I'm so afraid of it,
I just might shoot a monkey
if it jumped out on me.
- [Tom] Andy.
- Good day sir.
- [Mike] And I will
not call again.
(dramatic folk music)
♪ On the wings of
a snow white dove ♪
♪ He sends his pure sweet love ♪
♪ A sign from above ♪
- [Crow] Steve Urkel's
(indistinct) museum.
- [Mike] I got nipple rub.
- [Tom] Oh him.
- [Brian] That's
WL Slogan's farm
that we studied
about right there.
- [Tom] WL.
- You think they'll let
us go look in the barn?
- Yeah, let's go look in it.
Besides we might find something.
- Tim run up to the farmhouse
and see if they'll let us
go down to the barn
and look around, okay.
- Yes sir.
- [Tom] Rock them
with your physique.
- [Crow] Can I
borrow a cup of shirt.
- I bet she doesn't
want us around here.
- [Mike] I don't
want you around here.
- Okay, hey you all come on!
- [Tom] You guys
can use the toilet
but she says I can't.
- [Crow] So
these three are all
majoring in Boggy Creek studies.
- [Mike] Yeah.
And he falls in and
gets eaten by pigs.
- Late in the afternoon Logan
came out of the field there,
driving his cows.
- [Tom] And one of
them blew a tire.
- He had to have put them
in that stall right there.
But it was in this barn
where he saw the creature.
- [Tom] Yeah when you major
in Boggy Creek studies,
you can write your own
ticket on Wall Street
after you graduate.
- [Crow] Okay people without
shirts, please put them on
and people with shirts,
please take them off.
- You know they said Slogan
was in his late 60's.
- [Tom] God I said that well.
- I think it was
in about 63 or 64.
- It was 64.
- That's correct, it was
in the fall of the year.
In fact it was probably
about this time of day,
late in the afternoon.
- [Crow] Geeze,
do a push up kid.
- Coming to left field he drove
those cows over
here in the stall.
- [Tom] Turn off the lights
and let me project my thoughts.
- [Mike] Come on get up there.
You in there.
- [Tom] You're in so much
trouble jumping over the moon.
Have a good time
in there you two.
- [Mike] I remember
he had cheese cloth
over it at this point.
(rooster crows)
- [Tom] Sure, crow
now it's 11:30.
(eerie music)
- [Crow] The cows had a
mutilation they had to go to.
- [Tom] If I'm not
mistaken that's (hollers)!
- [Mike] He touts a dashing
figure in his white Panama hat.
- [Tom] Looks like Tom Wolfe.
- [Crow] Well no sense
closing the barn door
after the cows, hey I
invented an aphorism.
(eerie music)
- [Tom] Ted Nugent,
slash Rob Zombie.
- Cher.
- Yeah, Cher.
- [Tom] Hey legend how's
the continuing going?
- [Crow] Well
no more corn liquor
on my Total for breakfast.
- [Mike] Well, I'll be
damn, farmers do exist.
- [Croooo] I am so much
better than this barn.
(upbeat folk music)
♪ Hey I was driving
down the road ♪
♪ Looking for a waffle house
drinking lots of Wild Turkey. ♪
♪ Yee-Hoo ♪
(doors close)
- Knock it off you big lizard.
- You knock it off
too you big brown elf.
- Hey, hey, hey you
two, come on, come on,
what are you fighting about?
- I don't know.
- The usual I guess.
- Well, oh, now you made me
forget what I came up here for.
- Well, I'll help you Mike.
I'll just use a flashback
like in the movie.
It was 15 or 20 seconds
ago, I remember it
like it was just yesterday.
(dramatic music)
Cervo and I were fighting
about god knows what
and you came in
and separated us.
After a smathering of dialogue,
you discovered that you
forgot why you're here.
(dramatic music)
There that should take
care of it for you Mike.
- Well, your flashback
was a little sketchy
in that it told me nothing.
- Here let me give it a shot.
It was a few years back, long
before Croooow's flashback.
I saw two well muscled
Olympian figures
locked in gymnasial sport.
Suddenly the cracken appeared,
casting assunder
the two demi gods
and then engaging them
into a Socratic symposium
on the various
similitude of memory.
(dramatic music)
And then it starts
to get a bit hazy.
- That's amazing Cervo,
you're better than that guy
who wrote that thing
about remembering stuff.
- Thank you.
- Okay, spread out you two
naughty-pated mushrooms.
I'll show you what
actually happened.
(dramatic music)
Okay there's these two
objects I can't quite,
oh, okay now a big blue shadows.
Man, this is awful I can't
make heads or tails out of,
oh wait a minute, I just
figured it out, I remember,
I came up here to
get my contacts.
(laughs)
- Of course it all
makes sense now.
- We'll be right back.
- Hey next time I'm gonna have
a car chase in my flashback.
- Oh cool.
(upbeat music)
(upbeat folk music)
- [Mike] That was Alan Jackson.
- Tim, hand me that
map out of there.
I'm gonna check something here.
- [Mike] I'm gonna
look at we for awhile.
- That sign back there
said Sulfur River.
- Are we here yet?
- We're close.
Got about a mile or so more.
- Good, I can finally
change these clothes.
- [Crow] Well
you can go ahead
and change your clothes
now if you want.
That'll be okay, no really.
(engine revs)
- [Mike] Man these bushes
are right on my bumper.
(car swerves)
- Thank goodness for the
Jeep's breaking distance
of 500 yards.
- [Crow] He suddenly
became a senior citizen.
(eerie music)
- [Tom] Wait, we got
firearms but we don't
have any liquor.
(Tom hums)
- You all wait in the jeep.
- [Crow] Me and the
castrato will check this out.
- [Mike] Guess what fell
out of the monster's pocket.
- [Tom] Posing for their
spring break pictures.
- Hey Doc, what is it?
- Mike is batch, oh, oh.
- Looks like a dead deer.
- [Crow] I know, I know, oh.
- Let's go look at it.
- No way I'm not gonna
go down there and look
at a dead deer.
- [Crow] Just horrible.
- [Tom] Oh man, oh my
friends got me drunk
and left me out here,
what time is it man?
- Looks like a car or truck
hit him, not long ago either.
- What happened to his head?
- I don't know, what
happened to the car or truck
is the question.
- I don't believe any car
or truck hit this deer.
- Why do you say this.
- Something's been eating
on it's right hindquarter.
- It doesn't matter, let's
get it out of the road
before somebody else runs
over it and has a wreck.
- I still don't believe any
car or truck hit this deer.
- [Mike] You need to work
on your camel toe son.
- Well, it doesn't
matter probably bobcat,
coon or something,
who knows, maybe it
belongs to the creature.
- [Crow] Hey can I get
a sheet or some underpants
or something?
- [Tom] Your head has
a retractable dome.
(eerie music)
- [Mike] Well this
roadkill ain't that bad.
- [Tom] Hey man what
kind of camping is this,
there's no RV hookups.
- [Crow] I claim
this land for Arkansas.
- We're close to the swamp.
- [Tom] Okay Ponce de Leon.
- We're gonna make camp
right here, right here.
- [Mike] Oh, man, I left
my hose on all night.
(grunts)
- [Crow] Okay sniff
your arm sweat, calm down,
that's it.
- [Tom] Hey everybody I
managed to cram my ass
into these shorts.
- [Mike] Robin Williams.
- That's pretty good Tim.
- [Tom] He needs a bra.
- In fact, I'd say that
that's pretty close
to what it actually looks like.
- Let me see.
- You've got to be kidding.
- Nope, it fits all
the descriptions.
- You mean to tell me that
we're camped down here
in the swamp where that
thing might be living?
- Well, I think he's sexy.
- I think we're all crazy
if we don't go to town
and get a motel room.
- I wouldn't worry
a lot about it,
I don't think it's been
seen in a few days anyway.
Although they appear
to seem docile
and never intentionally
harmed anyone.
- [Tom] They do anyway.
- [Brian] There's
is one incident
that's always intrigued me.
- Seeing those underpants.
- [Brian] It was sometime in
the fall a few years back,
an elderly gentlemen by
the name of Otis Tucker
was on his way home from
grocery shopping in Texarcana,
when he had a blow out on
a lonely stretch of road
that runs parallel to the swamp.
- [Crow] Let's
watch and enjoy.
- [Mike] Fortunately
he was wearing pullups
because of his
frequent blowouts.
- [Tom] That flashback
wasn't color corrected
when it came back from the
lab so it's kinda dark.
- [Crow] Zip.
- [Otis] Oh good
Lord have mercy.
- [Tom] Oh yes?
- [Crow] I've gotta get home
and not talk to my wife.
- [Tom] No there's
my Johnny cake pan.
- [Crow] Yeah,
I gotta get going
I'm trying to cook a pork
shoulder on my exhaust manifold.
- [Otis] Hello!
- [Tom] Look, you
gonna keep filming
or are you gonna help
me with the tire?
- [Otis] Anybody there?
- [Mike] The woods are just
crammed with Y2K survivalists.
- [Crow] So the
guy changed a tire,
the believability rating
is quite high here.
- [Mike] Ken Burns six
part series, tire changing.
- [Crow] He had
a tight lug nut,
plus he had a bad back
which didn't help any.
- [Otis] Anybody there?
- [Tom] Just think of the
raccoons that have died
at this guy's hands.
(eerie music)
- [Crow] Otis didn't believe
in flashlight batteries.
(Otis hollers)
- Otis Tucker never
regained consciousness.
- [Mike] He was dead
so it makes sense.
- He stayed in the hospital
for over two years.
Therefore, he was never
able to tell anybody
what happened to him.
(upbeat music)
- [Lynn] The circles,
what do they represent?
- [Tom] Round things.
- Well, see this first
line that's 200 meters,
then we come into 75, 50 and
of course the square here,
that represents the home base.
So we should be able
to sit right here
and monitor this whole area.
- Oh, so you mean if
anything approaches the camp,
we should be able to see it.
- It depends on how sensitive
we set these censors.
For instance there are
two ways we can do it.
We can set this up for weight
or we an set it up for height.
Now let's run this
first test on weight.
For instance, Tanya
is about 110 pounds,
so I'm gonna enter that in now.
- [Tom] 107.
- Okay, Tim I'd
say is about 130.
- [Mike] Excuse me 128.
- That's in, now there's
one other thing we gotta do.
- [Crow] Love.
- We need to set this at
anything over 100 pounds
to set it off, so 800 pounds
because like snakes
or small animals,
raccoons or something we
don't want it to set it off.
Let's raise him on the
radio and run our test.
- Tanya, do you read?
- [Tom] Third grade level.
- Yeah, I read, just
me and a whole bunch
of blood thirsty mosquitoes.
- Tim do you read?
- Loud and clear.
Hey Doc, how long you
want me to wait out here,
I'm getting hungry?
- Here let me talk to stick boy.
[Mike] That boy's always hungry.
- Okay, gang, we're
all set up here,
I'll tell you what I
want you guys to do now.
- [Crow] Me.
- [Brian] I want you to
start back to the base
and I want you to
come directly at me
and try to come in a
straight line, okay?
- Gotcha.
- Okay Dad,
I mean, professor who
is in no way my dad
giving me a role on this movie.
- Okay, okay, there's Tim see.
Okay, see this
dot, that's Tanya,
who just broke the first
200 meters right there.
- [Tom] I hope the
radar doesn't detect
I'm not wearing a bra.
- [Crow] Nature is growdy.
- Hey this baby is
working like a charm.
- Oh the marvels
of modern science.
- [Tom] Boy Tim's a real
strong blip on my gaydar.
(radar alarms)
- Brian, what's that?
- [Crow] That's the computer
I was just telling you about.
- I don't know something broke
to the southwest corner
of the parameter there.
- [Lynn] It's
moving toward Tanya.
- Don't panic now
hold this a minute.
It could be a deer, it
could be a cow or anything.
- [Tom] It could
be Bernie Tomlin,
it could be a Pilates
machine, anything.
- Let me put some weight
in and see what it says.
I'll go to 250.
Oh crap it wiped out
my identity again.
Left corner.
- [Crow] I'm gonna
download "Palm,"
it should only take seven hours.
- [Tom] He is separately
miced for your convenience.
- I got it cornered now.
- [Mike] William Perry.
- We got a problem.
- [Crow] Hey hold on I gotta
announce the luncheon specials.
- Tanya, I don't wanna
alarm anybody but--
- Run.
- Just broke
the southwest corner
of the parameter.
Do you hear or see anything?
- [Tom] I hear my tummy growling
and I see lots
and lots of trees.
- Doc, I don't see a thing.
- [Tom] Can I get a drop slip.
- It's moved more than 50
yards, in the last few seconds.
- Something's out there and
it's heading toward Tanya.
Tell them to come in Brian.
- You guys I want you
to come back to the base
and I want you to come back
quickly, Tim come on, move it,
get in here now,
come on Tanya, move.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Lucy braless.
- I want you to stay on this
mic and watch that screen,
here take this.
I'm going out there,
there's something wrong.
- Run, girl, run!
- Go, fight, go.
- Keep me posted.
- [Crow] Someone had
a huge Toblerone bar.
- [Mike] Doctor
batch, let's fall.
- [Tom] Let's get
physical, physical.
- Come on, come on, give
me the walkie talkie.
- Is it him?
- I don't know, keep going,
get to camp.
- [Tom] Do you like panty hose?
- [Crow] A bunch of
smooze are attacking.
- Doc.
- Yeah, come on,
I read you.
- It's close to you.
- Left or right.
- [Tom] It depends on which
way you're facing idiots.
- I smell you.
- You're in Georgia
aren't you?
- You better say something!
- [Crow] Oh I didn't
have anything prepared.
- [Tom] I better run in and
trim an inch off my shorts.
- Thank god you're all right.
- What's going on?
- [Mike] Okay, legs
bent, butt protruded,
stomach pooched out, good.
- You all right?
- I'm okay.
- Brian, it's gone.
It was there then
it just disappeared.
- Gone.
- Fast.
- I've never scene anything
move that fast in my life.
- Where is Tim?
- I don't know.
- Oh no.
Let me check this out.
- [Tom] Won't you get
rid of missile command.
- My god he's not there.
Wait a minute.
He is not there.
- [Croooows] Viv Savage,
research assistant.
- Boo.
- [Mike] Damn, he's alive.
- Boy you scared
the shit out of us.
- [Croooows] Every night we
have to tie Tim in the trees
to keep him safe
from the creature.
- [Tom] A short, short trailer.
- [Mike] The target
website is boring.
- [Croooows] Uh-oh,
please don't be splayed.
- [Tom] Where do you wanna
go today, how about Arkansas.
Etiquette father,
domineering mother.
- [Croooows] Woodsy's out
there and he's yelling
at someone for littering.
You've got monster.
(eerie music)
- [Mike] A computer performed
an illegal operation.
- [Tom] Here comes
greater than dah.
- [Mike] I'll just
enter go away.
- Oh no.
- [Croooows] The thing we're
looking for is coming, oh no.
- I thought you'd be
in the target area.
Wake up, hey we got a visitor.
- [Mike] He wakes
them up once an hour
just to see their underpants.
- Got a visitor, come on.
Look at this.
- [Tom] I am doing great
at this free cell game.
- He just passed 200 meter
parameter right there.
- [Croooows] It's a menorah.
- I can't take anymore of this.
- Oh no, let's just
watch it for a minute.
- Doc are you sure it's him?
- Positive.
I just put in 350 pounds,
then I went to 400
and he's exactly where I
thought he'd be in between.
- Doc let's get out of here.
- Wait just a minute,
we're gonna watch him.
- [Croooows] Doc does
a lot of watching.
- [Tom] Uh-huh.
- Look, he stopped.
- He stopped Troy.
- Here he goes, he's moving
north away from us now.
- [Croooows] He's riding a
moose and he has a weapon.
- Look at him, he's
circling this camp.
I don't believe it.
- [Tom] I hope he
likes my fright wig.
- Just watch him,
he's turning back,
he's coming across the 50 now.
- [Croooows] He's
at the 40, the 30.
- Doc, he's headed for the camp.
(screams)
- Hold it, shut up,
hold it!
- Tim stop screaming.
- [Brian] We lost power,
be quiet, I gotta hear.
Don't panic, nobody panic.
I gotta be able to hear,
now it's important.
Get that camera over there.
(upbeat music)
- You guys Pearl's calling,
you guys Pearl's calling,
you guys Pearl's calling.
- Okay Gypsy.
- Pearl's calling.
- Yes, what now?
- Mike, Croooow,
Cervo, Gypsy, Mike,
I don't want to frighten you
but there's a huge
mysterious monster
of some sort lurking.
- Oh, Bobo.
- His mighty odor precedes him.
- Bobo.
- Traces of his fat
left like smoke, yes.
- Bobo.
- Stop that, the point
is you get a legend,
you get lumpy tourists spending
their disposable incomes.
So to get it all going, country
legend Hank Brainguy Junior
has penned a haunting,
evocative song about said beast.
(guitar music)
♪ You put around these
parts long enough ♪
♪ And you might hear tell
of some skulking creature ♪
♪ Laundering around
the wooded swamp ♪
♪ Hairy and beast-like ♪
♪ Sending a mess of
heap of trouble ♪
♪ Among the good folks
living up yonder ♪
♪ Now some folks
don't pay no mind ♪
♪ Other folks will tell
you it don't mean no harm ♪
♪ Yes, Mrs. Idy Lou, she'll
look away with her bad eye ♪
♪ And she'll look at you
straight on with her good eye ♪
♪ And she'll tell you she
don't know nothing about it ♪
♪ But then she gets a little
shutter like she might ♪
♪ She just might know
something about it ♪
♪ Gather around all ye
friends and neighbors ♪
♪ And (indistinct)
there's a creature who
lives in the swamp ♪
That's it.
- So clearly there is
some sort of creature.
We really haven't hammered
out all the details.
Please excuse us now
we have to get busy
making keychains, T-shirts,
little plastic figurines, bye.
- Bobo.
- Shut up,
get back into the theater!
(hollers)
(doors opening)
- Did you put gas
in the generator?
(all chattering)
- Cut it out, you gotta
be quiet I gotta hear.
- [Tom] Class must be fun.
- Give me that gun, quick.
- [Mike] Do the
scary face thing.
- Give me the dart.
- Oh my god Brian, not that.
- Listen it may be the
only chance we have
against him, I'm gonna try
and stop him right now.
- [Crow] With
this Shaffer pen.
- Okay, now listen,
it's important.
Do not panic, 'cause we may
not ever get this chance again.
Now you've gotta be
quiet so I can hear.
- [Mike] Use your indoor voice.
- Tim, where's the gas?
- It's just outside.
- All right, you
get the gas can,
you guys stay right here
and quiet, let's go move.
- You all be careful.
- I don't mean that.
- All right, hold it.
- No, don't hold that,
what are you.
- Let me see that light.
Quiet in there.
- My nail polish.
- Move to the end,
hold it right there.
- [Mike] You look
beautiful in this light.
- Quiet!
- He's the one who tripped.
Where's the gas can?
- [Crow] Sorry
I'm not mechanical.
- It's under there.
- All right, get it, come on.
- [Mike] Okay, now you
need to emulate yourself
to distract the monster.
- [Tom] Good make sure
you get lots on the grass.
(laughs)
- [Crow] Doc
am I overdressed?
- Hurry, crank it.
- Okay.
(generator engine revs)
- [Tom] Oh he's got a
third nipple developing ah.
- [Crow] They can
play night games now.
- [Tom] Where's
the (indistinct).
(eerie music)
(growls)
- [Crow] Can I
borrow some charcoal?
- [Mike] My wonderful
discovery, let's kill it.
- [Tom] You feel lucky, punk?
- Talk to me.
- Nah, I don't wanna
bend your ear.
Ooh, right in the sore.
- [Mike] Hey a flu shot, thanks.
(growls)
- [Crow] Hey
hot shot you ever
used a tranquilizer
gun rectally before?
- [Tom] As soon as I
get free of this tree,
I'm gonna be so over there.
I guess the believability rating
just spiked a little higher.
- Yeah.
(growls)
- [Tom] Wow does that hurt.
- [Brian] What
kept attracting him
to come back around
our camp puzzled me.
The dart gun was a mistake,
he simply reached
and pulled it out.
- [Crow] It was as lewd
gesture now that I think of it.
- [Tom] The (indistinct)
is attack pigeons.
- [Brian] Everyone was so
shook up after last night
including myself I decided
to tell them one more story
that was a little bit
on the lighter side.
The story I've heard
goes something like this.
Oscar Colpotter was his name.
(Croooow laughs)
- [Mike] A dramatic reenactment.
- Just what are you looking for?
- I'm looking for the
Sears Roebuck catalog.
- Well I guess you're gonna
mess up the whole house for it?
- I will if I have
to, I'd rather do that
than mess up my pants.
- We certainly don't want that,
the catalog's on the back porch.
- [Crow] Pat Conroy at home.
- [Tom] Like he's suddenly
shy about going in his pants.
(dramatic folk music)
- [Mike] No, no the south
is gonna do it again.
(laughs)
- [Tom] A little
something for the ladies.
- [Brian] This was their house
their first year of marriage.
(growls)
- [Tom] Lilian Broyle looks
different without her makeup.
(eerie music)
- Myrtle help!
- [Crow] It's
a poop emergency,
she snaps into action.
- Hold on Oscar!
- [Tom] But I back up
to renew the truck.
- Myrtle help
- I said hold on Oscar,
I'm coming!
- [Crow] Is the
Miller's town Mike?
- What the hell was
that after you Oscar?
- Hell if I know Myrtle
I thought it was you,
it's was the wildest
thing I ever seen.
- Well you gonna get
that stuff off of you?
- Oh, yeah, hand me
that catalog in there
and let me clean myself up.
- It's gonna take more
than a catalog Oscar,
if you ask me it's gonna
take the water hose.
(hollers)
- Some mess, man,
so much, golly.
- [Brian] How much truth
there is to this story,
I couldn't say.
I can tell you for sure
that Oscar Colpottter
is a retired attorney
form Texarkana
and is known from time to time
to have had a drinking problem.
- [Crow] Feces.
- [Brian] Anyway back to
the more serious side.
- [Tom] A urine story.
- [Brian] I reached
Deputy Williams by phone
and arranged a meeting
at the local coffee shop.
I decided I will not tell
him or anyone at this point
about seeing the creature
myself last night.
And I advised Tim and
the girls to do the same.
- [Mike] Sorry am
I talking too much?
- [Brian] I wanted to hear
from Williams and his version
of what he said it looked
like without my input.
- [Tom] For a transcript
of the poop scene
send $2.99 to journal graphics.
- Okay, you all don't
forget anything now.
- [Tom] Remember to feed Tim.
- Morning.
- Morning, sir.
You must be Deputy Williams.
- You Dr. Lockhart?
- I am, let's get some coffee.
- [Crow] I'll just
have a Frappuccino.
- Well that day I'd been
fishing down on Sulfur River,
it was late in the
afternoon, it wasn't dark.
And I went to the shed.
- Oh no not another story
about that.
- [Tom] I was right tired
from swinging a night stick
at the skulls of suspected
marijuana users all night.
- [Mike] A stray boat
has followed me home.
- Did you catch any fish?
- A few.
- Take them down to the
shed and clean them,
I don't want them
smelly things up here.
- [Crow] Oh they're
her own children,
how can she say that?
- [Mike] I hope we're having
whipped cudzoo for dinner.
- [Tom] Why is she
whittling a tennis ball?
- [Crow] You know I
kept walking like that
for quite awhile the end.
- [Mike] By that point
my hair had blanketed
my football head.
(eerie music)
- [Tom] Suddenly I was
attacked by a moppet.
- [Crow] Where's the
money you son of a bitch.
(eerie music)
- [Mike] Now Bobby you give
the fish back to the nice man.
- [Tom] Sorry he
just unriddling.
- [Mike] Shazam.
- No one believes me, my
wife doesn't even think
I seen such a thing.
That thing was huge,
his eyes glaring out
under that hairy forehead.
- [Mike] He had a pointed skull.
- [Crow] I'm sorry I
wasn't paying attention, what?
- You think it
meant you any harm?
- No, I think he just
smelled the dead fish
and just came up to investigate.
- [Mike] I can see doing that.
- By the way have you
talked to old man Krenshaw?
- [Tom] I told you
never to bring him up.
- I don't believe I've
ever heard of him.
- He's an old man, I bet
he's lived on the bottoms
all his life.
- [Crow] Sam and Timothy.
- He'll be able to
tell you something.
- [Mike] Later that dull story.
- All right you guys, it's
ready come and get it.
- What are we having?
- Bologna sandwiches
and pork and beans.
- Great, one of my favorites.
- Well, it's not one of mine.
- [Crow] Huh, oh I
didn't see you there,
you're camouflaged.
- Tanya do you have my blush?
- Blush.
- [Mike] Blush, what
the hell is blush.
- [Tanya] No I don't
have your blush.
- Guys I don't wanna
be down here anyway,
let's into town and get a motel.
- [Mike] I don't understand
anything she says.
- Are we going in the
swamp with your guys?
- Not today.
- You're gonna leave
us a rifle aren't you?
- [Mike] What is she saying now?
- A rifle, you wouldn't know
what to do with it if I did.
- [Crow] To hell
with you and your stupid
wished to be protected.
- Wanna bet?
- Ooh, ga-zing.
- [Brian] Tim and I began
searching behind the camp
hoping we might find hair
or even a small blood sample
from where the creature had
torn off through the woods.
- [Tom] We only assumed
he'd torned off though,
it's possible he beat
cheeks or busted a hump.
- [Crow] All right
one of these scenes.
- [Mike] Hey calm down.
- [Tom] Oh I hope they wrestle.
- [Mike] Come on.
- Can you drive the jeep?
- Sure why?
- This is crazy.
- What do you mean by that?
- We're fools for
just sitting here.
- [Tom] Yes you
could be wrestling.
- Who says that thing
only comes out at night?
- [Tom] Now I can't
understand her.
- It could be
watching us right now.
- [Tom] Yes, he's waiting
for you to wrestle!
(upbeat folk music)
- These fools are
fixing to ride.
- [Croooows] Something about
food for a fist full of racks.
Okay we'll go with that.
- [Tom] Oh good, oh good,
oh good, they're gonna drive
to some place where
they can wrestle.
- [Mike] Okay, (indistinct).
- [Tom] I just want
them to wrestle.
♪ He sends his pure sweet love ♪
- [Brian] Trooper Williams
left out one important fact,
he said nothing
about the foul odor
or the creature emits which
was still very much present
many hours after Tim and
I were in the forest.
- [Tom] In fact wherever we
went there was a foul odor.
He must have just been
at every place we looked.
Mud, do you realize
what this means?
- [Crow] Sh,
Mike said stop it.
- [Mike] Tenita
Ticerum, naturalist.
- I knew we should have
stayed at the camp.
- Well, I don't believe
we came this way.
I don't remember
these mud holes.
- We have to had went
through several mud holes.
- But not these,
they're too deep.
- [Tom] Bob do you believe this.
- Do you know how to put that
thing in four wheel drive?
- [Tom] Whoa.
- Hell no I don't I've never
been in one of these things
until I came up on
this stupid trip!
- Then you just better hold on.
- [Crow] Hey they're using
their jeep to do things,
I thought you only drive
those things to Starbucks.
- [Mike] It's the Arkansas
remake of wages of fear.
- [Tom] Checking on the land
they bought from the Clinton's.
(engine revs)
- [Crow] Sunday we
turn a giant mud pit
into a giant mud pit.
- [Tom] Whoa must
have hit a gusher.
- Yes, oh no, she's
unzipping the car.
- You've done it now.
- Me, it was your idea
to go riding around
in the first place.
- [Tom] There's an
easy way to solve this.
- Put the damn thing
in four wheel drive
and let's get out of here.
- I don't know how
to put the damn thing
in four wheel drive.
- Uh darn thing ladies.
- Maybe there's a manual
in here that will tell us
how to do it.
- It's gonna take
more than four wheels
to get us out of this
hole, like about eight.
- [Crow] Eight wheels,
so it's come to this.
- Quit joking and we've
gotta figure this thing out.
It's getting late.
- I'm not joking, the mud's
almost up to our doors.
- Look, here it is, this
is all we have to do.
- [Tom] Get naked and wrestle!
- [Mike] That's
enough now, come on.
- There, that should
be in four wheel drive.
- I told you Cervo.
- Crank it up
and let's get out of here.
- [Tom] This movie's very damp,
I think it's one of
our dampest movies.
- Me too.
- Uh-huh.
- [Crow] Now is
this a flashback,
a little bit confused.
- [Mike] Probably stuck
in their own makeup.
- [Ted] There's a red
scarf floating in the air.
Oh no it's her,
she's camouflaged.
- Camouflaged.
- It's no use, we're gonna
have to walk out of here.
- Oh my god, don't even
suggest such a thing.
It'll be dark soon.
- [Crow] They've synchronized
so they're both crabby.
(eerie music)
- I'm open for your suggestions.
- Well blow the horn.
- Blow the horn.
- [Tom] Do I look like
I know how to do that?
- What good is that gonna do?
- Well, Tim and Brian
are down here somewhere,
maybe they'll hear it.
- No, Tim's too thin to hear.
- Tim and Brian have probably
been back at the camp
for hours resting,
eating, dry, comfortable.
- Don't tell me that stuff.
- Sing it instead.
- Trade places with
me, I wanna try.
- No way, you're just
gonna make it worst.
- [Tom] Yeah well you're flat.
- Well, we're lost
remember, I'm not gonna go
just start walking
up in these woods
looking for a camp that we
have no idea where it is.
- [Tom] Hey there's a
point of view monster
headed right for them.
- [Mike] I'd like
to think the legend
for allowing us to place
a camera in his helmet.
- It might get a little cool
before the night's over.
- We do have a heater
in this thing don't we?
- Yep, I believe we do.
- How much gas we got?
- We have E gallons.
- Over half a tank.
- Good.
- [Tom] Wait, which half?
- Today's Tuesday, they should
find us before the weekend.
And we'll run out of gas.
- You got me into this
mess, I wanna get out
and I wanna go home.
All we gotta do now is find
a Tombstone to mark the spot
where you buried us.
- [Crow] I think the normally
crisp Charles B. Pierce's
writing style is
falling apart here.
- [Tom] Ah, not looking
for them is great.
He's smoking a swizzle stick.
- It's almost eight o'clock.
- Time for Dharma and Greg.
- We're gonna have
to go find them.
- How, it's 15 miles
out of this bottom.
- [Crow] Wow you could
file papers in that party ad.
- They have our
only transportation.
- Where the hell could they be?
- Leslie probably talked
Tanya into going into town.
Probably looking for something
besides bologna to eat.
- [Tom] Tim's humor
falls a little flat.
(coyote howls)
- [Mike] Look at that makeup,
it looks like she's looking
out of a charred log.
- What was that?
- What was what?
- That sound we just heard.
- It sounded like a wolf.
- A wolf.
- [Tom] Do you think
it will survive?
- You mean there's wolves
in these woods too?
- Also snakes,
bobcats, alligators.
- That's enough,
don't tell me anymore.
- [Tom] Wolves, where, where,
bobcats, alligators, no, no.
- God, there's a
winch on the front.
- What's that?
- Something to get
you unstuck with.
- Well why in the hell
haven't you mentioned it
before now.
- You didn't ask, besides
I don't know how to use it.
- Stupid we have the
manual right here.
Hand me the flashlight.
- [Mike] Perhaps they could
fashion their eyeliner
into a crude spear
for protection.
- Okay it says you
keep the motor running,
you pull, keep the
vehicle in neutral,
you pull out on the cable until.
- [Crow] And
then it just ends.
(eerie music)
- [Tom] Now I'm lost,
where the hell am I?
(upbeat music)
- [Mike] Here we go.
Want me to get that
windshield for you?
- [Crow] Apparently
Candies made a hiking boot.
- Here it is right here.
- The ground, right where
it's supposed to be.
There's a series of symbols
that carry no meaning.
- See there's the
cable right there,
you just pull out on that.
- [Crow] They're lucky
they get cable out here.
- I knew I'd be
doing all the work.
- [Tom] I'm the mack truck
bulldog, (imitates dog barking).
- [Mike] Two butch looking
woman not in a Suburu,
something's wrong here.
(screams)
- [Tom] Mike, Mike,
she's in the mud,
they have to wrestle.
- No.
(Tim cries)
All her woodland friends
are laughing at her.
(laughs)
- McLintock.
- Look woman, if you
wanna get out of here,
you better get down
here and help me!
- Well I do wanna
get out of here.
- [Crow] But I enjoy
seeing you in the mud,
it's a difficult choice.
- [Tom] Well now that
they're in the mud
I'm actually feeling kind
of ashamed of myself.
Is this really what I wanted?
- [Mike] That's the brake cable,
you're pulling right
out of the car.
(eerie music)
- [Crow] Ranger
Rick goes bazerk.
- [Tom] They're not
shooting day for night,
it's more like 4:30
for five o'clock.
- [Mike] Okay, I'll
go talk to the truck.
- [Crow] Now they
stumble on the Rose Law firm
billing records.
- [Tom] Well, my boy and I
are here to help you ladies.
They're making blueberry
vermouth gelatin.
- [Crow] You know I'm
at least as tense as I was
during "A Very Brady Christmas."
- Oh my god,
Leslie, there he is.
(screams)
- [Mike] He is must have
a better camera than me,
I can't see a thing.
(screams)
- [Tom] Oh they must
have seen a swamp mouse.
- [Crow] They should get a
swamp chair and stand on it.
(eerie music)
(Tim humming)
- [Mike] Well, my rowdy
friends never showed up.
- Doc, what time is it now?
- Almost 11.
- I feel something's bad wrong.
- [Crow] I think I'm
feeling better about us though.
- Yeah, so do I.
I'll tell you what let's do,
I don't think we can wait
any longer.
- Oh yes.
- Take the rifle and
we're going to the swamp.
- [Mike] Two ant
sections are attacking.
- [Crow] I got a
new chest hair today.
- [Tom] Software by RoyBob's
feet and software Texarkana.
- Is he back?
- No but the girls are.
- Are you sure?
- Now do you see
how slow that's moving?
- Remember Tanya just had
reconstructive knee surgery.
- That's them all right, get
over there, get on the bed.
- [Crow] Put
on something lacy.
- We're gonna play this out.
- [Mike] Do I have
to be on the bed?
- It's them all right.
Just relax now, let's
just wait just a second.
- [Tom] I think it's
rice riding piggy back.
- [Crow] Playing it out.
- [Mike] Boy it sure
is playing out, huh?
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
- [Crow] We're playing
it out stay on the bed.
- Come in ladies.
- [Tom] And so the completely
pointless stretch of movie
whimpers out like
a small dying rat.
- [Mike] You know this
is almost too painful,
this playing it out?
- Yeah.
- [Brian] You wanna
tell me about it?
- I'm gonna lend her.
- [Crow] Well,
thank you Tanya,
our adventures
started in base camp
the rummy boonjobs
were all around us.
- We stuck the jeep.
- Up your, what's that word?
- That figures.
- That ain't all.
- Did you wreck it?
- No we saw it.
- You saw what?
- I knew they
wouldn't believe us.
Damn it Doc, we saw it.
You and Tim saw it,
we believed you,
why can't you believe us?
- [Mike] Why can't
I believe them,
was it my toilet training?
- Tanya, did you see it?
- Yeah.
- She wants me.
- [Brian] It wasn't that
I didn't believe them,
I guess I just wanted to get
back at them a little bit
for what they put Tim and I
through for the last six hours.
- [Mike] No you can't surf
in Arkansas, follow the law.
- [Tom] Unfortunately
he is the life guard.
- [Crow] I wouldn't drown
my rheumatism's acting up.
- [Mike] Lay in the
sand and shut up.
- Howdy.
- You going hunting or fishing?
- Well, we're
heading down river.
- How you traveling,
you wading or riding?
- Hopes to be riding,
you rent any boats.
- Well I got one I'll rent
you five dollars an hour.
And I got a larger boat I
can rent you for $25 a day,
everything furnished.
- We'll take the
one for all day.
- Good, I'll fix you one.
- That's a big expense.
- If you wanna go right
down there and wait
and I'll, we'll bring it around.
- [Mike] We just
gotta build it first.
(doors closing)
- Okay, let's move them out.
- Cervo what are you doing?
- Oh, I've taken
up whittling Mike.
- Oh, well whittling like
the guy in the movie.
- Oh not exactly no.
You see whittling technology
has been stagnant,
so we saw an
opportunity, we moved in,
we bought a little
outfit in Kentucky.
Hey where's that livestock!
- Somebody got their--
- I don't care, get it going.
Well, now we've got 14,000
employees and 23 plants,
mostly overseas but I still
got the one in the states,
(indistinct) you know?
- Yeah, wow, you know,
all these machinery,
all these people
and what do you make?
- Well listen the product
has always been good,
we have not altered
the product at all.
We provide the same stick
that's a little narrower
at one end, go
ahead keep that one.
- Thanks.
- Oh, that's Brazilian
mahogany by the way,
it whittles fairly well.
- Oh, Brazilian mahogany,
Cervo you're decimating the
rain forest to make these.
- Listen Sting, you wanna
see the cost figures.
- You know I gotta say it sort
of lost some of the charm,
some of the folksiness--
- Yeah, hold on,
hey get back to work!
- [Workers] Union,
union, union, union!
- Oh sure like
that's gonna happen.
You call the
Pinkerton's for me Mike,
I gotta go get the hose.
- We'll be right back.
- [Tom] Yeah, you take a
swim you mutts! (laughs)
(upbeat music)
- [Mike] Hey look at
that a whole beach
full of research assistants.
And hut.
- How far is it
down to Crenshaw's?
- Well according
to Deputy Williams,
it's about two miles down river.
- Tanya we should have
brought our swimsuits
so we could stay for awhile
instead of going off
on this stupid safari.
- [Tom] She envies my
smoked aviator glasses.
- I hear the boat
coming, let's go.
- [Crow] It's
really huge below deck.
Now this is the boat
they should have taken
over that mountain
in (indistinct).
- You wouldn't know a fellow
by the name of
Crenshaw would you?
- Everybody up and down
this river knows Crenshaw.
- How far down river
is it to his place?
- Oh by crow's fly or by boat?
- By boat.
- Well, I'd say about three
mile, first cabin on the right.
- Thank you very
much, let's move out.
(boat engine runs)
- [Mike] The first motor.
- [Crow] Hey Mark
Knoffler is hot.
- [Tom] I'm gonna enjoy the
serenity of nature. (laughs)
(boat engine revs)
- [Mike] Wanna go buzz
the children's beach.
- This is great, I'm
polluting the water
and I'm making noise.
- [Tom] Is this a Bond
film all of a sudden?
- [Crow] You wanna help
us oppose jet ski regulation?
- [Tom] It's fun
that there are man.
He's gonna hit a
tree now, too bad.
- [Mike] Yeah, shame.
(dramatic music)
- [All Three] Go Boggy,
go Boggy, go, go!
(eerie music)
(hollers)
- [Tom] Oh man that's
a damn shame huh?
- [Mike] Well maybe they'll
circle back and chop him up.
(eerie music)
Okay, let's see
who rides who now.
- [Crow] We're gonna
start finding headless dead
jet skiers all over
the county highway.
(eerie music)
- [Mike] Go back
and get help boy.
- [Tom] Took away your jet ski,
let's see how you
like the water now.
- [Crow] Oh well
giving jet ski odds,
he's only got a couple
of weeks left anyway.
- [Tom] Yeah.
(eerie music)
♪ It was the third of December ♪
(indistinct)
- [Brian] These river bottoms
are truly a site to behold.
- [Tom] Whoa.
- [Brian] As we traveled
the river that day
it made me feel good.
Here the air is
clean and reminded me
that much of this
country is still
and should remain unspoiled.
- [Tom] As blue smoke
poured from my motor.
- [Brian] Moving
water and vegetation,
I was beginning to
understand how easy it is
for this creature to
survive and hide from men.
I'm convinced now that he
is more manlike than ever.
In every reported sighting,
he's always been seen
in an upright position
on his back two legs.
Bears, gorillas, orangutans
and such other animals
can walk about on two legs
but under stress or strain will
go down on all fours to run.
- [Mike] When I'm
stressed out I'll go down
on all fours and run too.
- [Brian] Crenshaws.
- [Crow] Be
careful, he could be
practicing his short game.
(Tim hums)
- [Mike] I'm gonna take a
break from my narration here
but I will be available
for questions.
♪ On the wings of a dove ♪
♪ Wings of a dove ♪
- [Mike] I put Tim in front
to absorb the first
hail of bullets.
(Tim imitates goat)
- [Tom] Yes, these
river bottoms are--
- Anyone home!
Knock on the door, Tim let's
see if anybody answers.
- [Mike] Oh is that what
I should do how novel.
(Tim knocks)
- [Crow] Tim
pulls reconnaissance.
Dictator for life,
Charles B. Pierce.
- I don't think anybody's home.
- [Tom] Yes these
river bottoms--
- [Mike] Okay.
- I don't like this at all.
- [Tom] Oh that's a change.
- That could be a mad goat.
- [Tom] Yes, I'm mad, mad.
- Hey, what are
you all doing here?
- [Tom] Oh it's the
Bazooka residence.
- You looking for
something to steal?
- [Brian] Nope, not exactly.
I saw your place from the river,
thought we'd stop for a minute.
- Well, boy if
everybody stopped here
that saw my place from the river
all I'd be doing
is entertaining.
- I met with Trooper Williams
in town the other day,
he suggested we stopped
down and see you.
- [Tom] He said nothing
about your marvelous breasts.
- Williams, how's he doing?
- He's doing fine.
- Doc, I think we'd
better head back home.
- [Mike] Is this the
one they call Tim.
- Come on down here
son and sit down,
my bark is a whole lot
worse than my bite.
You all have a seat.
- [Crow] Why don't you
all take the skin chair.
- How are you young ladies?
- My name is Brian
Lockhart, Doctor Lockhart.
- How you doing cousin?
- Fine.
This is Tanya, Leslie and Tim.
- Hi girls.
- Hey.
- [Mike] Randy Johnson's dad.
- You want some gal?
- Give me some.
- That a girl.
- [Crow] Oh god,
she thinks it's chew.
- [Tom] Tsk, tsk.
- You married ma'am?
- [Mike] Me I'm
married to my work.
- That sure is a
man's kind of woman.
- Mr. Crenshaw.
- I'm planning an abduction.
- You been living
down here long?
- I sure have.
I buried my truck
back over here in '46
and I ain't been nowhere else
except up the river since then.
- [Tom] Yeah, me too.
- We're from the university
and we're studying man.
- Oh, boy if you come
down here and study me,
you better be prepared
to stay for awhile.
- No sir but I would like
to ask you some questions,
if I could.
- Uh-huh.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Let me just
show you one cheek.
- You ain't with the
revenue boys are you son?
- [Mike] No but I
was a Beastie Boy.
- 'Cause if you are
I'll throw down on you
before nine gars
can gut a minnow.
- Why nine gars?
- Nope, like I said,
we're from the university,
studying the Boggy
Creek creature.
- [Mike] Why does my head hurt?
- The Boggy Creek creature huh?
- Uh-huh, huh.
- Well, I've known
that all my life, he's right
back over there in them woods.
- You ever seen him.
- Yeah, I see him
all the time, he was yelling
and bawling and carrying on.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah, I'm serious,
they woke me up around
here one morning a banging
and beating on the tub,
a man can't get a bit of
sleep around here for them.
- [Tom] I think he's getting
the creature mixed up
with the Allman Brothers.
- What the little one look like?
- [Mike] Well the little one
ended up with my features.
- Well cousin, the little one
looks just like the big one.
- Man that stain.
- Yeah, I guess.
- Here girl, you
want some of this?
- [Tom] No, it's a
naturally occurring cheese
from his body.
- What's the matter
with you girl, you sick?
- I am.
- [Mike] I love a
woman who vomits.
- That's sure is a
man's kind of woman.
- I'm gonna go check on Tanya.
- [Mike] Well, hell
there's another one.
(thunder cracks)
- It looks like there's
a storm coming up.
- [Tom] What do you think, Tim?
- It a bad one too.
- I think we better
head back down river.
Tim you wanna get the girls.
- Put your shirt on.
- It'll be dark here
in a little bit.
(thunder rolls)
- Boy, you don't wanna
get on that river
with a storm coming
up like this.
That water draws lightning.
- [Crow] Why don't I
just go ahead and kill you.
- Well, I got to go
tend to my fires.
- [Mike] Just
spreading my filth.
- Preparing land?
- Nope.
- Get a storm in these trees?
- None of my business is it?
- Nope.
You can wait in the
house with the girls
if you want too.
- [Tom] Grab yourself a broccoli
rubber band for your head.
- [Mike] Oh my god,
look at the bodies, oh.
- [Crow] I am the NRA.
- [Tom] Oh I sat on a dead pig.
- Brian come here.
What's he doing?
- [Mike] Never dig too deep
into what this guy's doing.
- What'd you find out?
- Nothing yet,
except he's up to no good.
- So are we gonna have
to spend the night here?
- The way the storm is,
and it's getting worse,
we'll be here for the night.
- Doc, here he comes.
- Okay, get over here and
sit down, quick, come on.
Now be quiet okay.
- [Crow] They
were acting casual
now they're all stiff and weird.
- [Mike] They're
not acting casual
and I'll have to kill them.
Well I got company I suppose
I should prop up the outhouse.
- [Crow] Oh dear I'm modest.
- [Tom] Uh-oh, I let
one and they know it,
I could just die.
- You say you're a doctor, boy?
- That's right.
- Then you must be pretty
good at patching up folks
that's all busted.
- Not that kind of
doctor, who's hurt?
- I thought all you doctors
was good at doctoring
on sick folks.
- [Mike] He's got me.
- Let me tell you
something cousin,
- [Crow] The
chunky Rembrandt.
- Me and you got to have a talk.
- [Tom] About how to get
rid of unwanted body.
- All nice and private.
- [Mike] Their eyes lock.
- I think we're overdue.
(humming)
(upbeat music)
- Come on over here
boy, hunker down,
I wanna show you something.
- [Crow] Never hunker down
within 10 yards of this guy.
(eerie music)
- [Mike] That shocks
my whole military wear.
- [Tom] He's way
cleaner than you.
Okay, look, my dad will
come up with the ransom,
he's a wealthy gorilla.
- [Crow] Hey you
dressed him in a little
one strap overalls.
- My god man.
- You've kidnapped
Jean Shallot.
- How long have you had this?
- I caught him a few days ago
in my trap, what do
you think about him?
- I think you're crazy
that's what I think.
- [Mike] Kind of a
fun crazy though.
- This thing's almost
dead, it's weak.
- [Tom] You've been
feeding it what you eat.
- That's what I got
you here for boy,
I want you to patch him up.
- [Crow] We'll need
clean towels, nevermind.
- Let me tell you
something old man.
- [Tom] Old, I was
carded yesterday.
- That's why that thing's
been going crazy lately,
jumping on people,
been around our camp,
followed the girls.
- [Mike] Say.
- It's after this little one.
That's why you're building
these fires around this camp,
'cause it's afraid of the fire.
That it?
- You finally smarting up
cousin, you figured it out.
- We've gotta get
this to a doctor.
- [Crow] Well, hopefully
not an Arkansas doctor.
- [Mike] Oh Crenshaw
you fascinate me.
(thunder roars)
- [Crow] Well there is
stuff living in his bathroom.
- Doc, what is it?
- [Mike] Hang on I'm gonna
belch the alphabet here.
- [Tom] Well I finally
got that gorilla down.
- Lord, have mercy, I've
got to get to my fires.
- Doc what happened in there?
- [Crow] I made a
pass at Crenshaw, okay.
- I saw it.
- You saw what?
- I saw the little creature.
(all chattering)
- No!
- Quiet.
(thunder roars)
- [Mike] Oh I
singed my pit hair.
- [Tom] Hey Thor has
really hit the skids.
- I don't wanna see it.
- [Crow] No woman should
have to see the little creature.
- You stay here Leslie and
watch that old man out here.
You guys come with me.
- [Mike] Don't try to sneak
in any dialogue here Tim.
- [Tom] Ooh, he must
be burning his bra.
Way to go.
- [Crow] Now
Crenshaw jumps in
and just tries to burn
off all his ticks.
- [Tom] The effort it
takes to try to balance it
on your shoulder, would
you just put your shirt on.
Legendary creatures
get all the chicks.
(growls)
- He ain't gonna make it if
we don't get him to a doctor.
- [Crow] I'm an expert
in undiscovered monkeys.
- Storm or no storm we have
to get him out of here.
(thunder roars)
- Hell.
- [Crow] (whimpers) Oh no
my perm is highly flammable.
- [Tom] What there's
another weird guy over there
with a fire.
I like this weird guy better.
(screams)
- [Crow] There's a
skidmark on the ceiling!
(screams)
The creature.
- Quiet, quiet, did you hear it?
- Yeah, I heard him.
- [Mike] Well stop
hearing stuff.
(growls)
- [Tom] Kent Hurbeck, three
months after retirement.
(growls)
- Just wait a minute, he's
on the porch, be quiet.
(screams)
- Good job.
(gun fires)
- That's it, stay in the house.
- Hold it man!
- Spread them,
oh no don't do that.
- It's raining out the fire,
he's coming in here on us.
- Put the shells
back in your pocket.
- You better let
me kill him now.
- You're not gonna
fire that gun man.
I mean it hold it.
Don't cross me this time old
man, in the house, right now.
- [Tom] Don't make
me seek Tim on you.
- Get in there.
- Okay, rain,
everybody's happy.
- Tim, (indistinct).
- [Tom] Off campus research
at the University of Arkansas.
- Okay man, give me the gun.
- You don't know what
you're doing boy.
- Don't let me tell you again
old man, give me the gun!
- [Mike] Crenshaw's
using his bathroom rug
as an air freshener.
- Now sit down in that chair,
get real comfortable, okay.
- [Mike] You asked for it.
- Stay right there old man.
- [Tom] Hey look I'm 28.
- Tim, hold his gun.
- It's heavy.
Take this.
- Oh.
- You know how to use it.
- No I don't.
- You stay here old man.
Watch him close.
(thunder roars)
- [Crow] Hello Tim.
- Old boy give me that gun.
Don't be as stupid
as that doctor.
- Noway.
- Noway,
Tim's instant catch phrase.
(growls)
Step into a Slim Jim.
(screams)
- [Mike] Oh, it's
just Ron Perlman.
(screams)
- [Tom] Oh man I killed
this little creature, oh hi.
(growls)
- [Crow] Congratulations
Mrs. Creek, it's a boy.
- Nobody's gonna
hurt you not anymore.
No you don't understand,
I'm gonna give you
what you came for.
- [Mike] Boggy Arnold
creature, where have you been?
Did you give him his
allergy medication?
- [Crow] Do you have
his teddy human also?
(growls)
- [Mike] By the way it
really stinks in here.
(growls)
(screams)
(slow music)
- Give me that gun boy.
- Tim comes through
in the clutch.
(screams)
- Get away from
me girl, get away.
- Hold it.
- [Tom] I've a plug of
Redman for you here.
- Better give me
them shells boy.
- [Mike] Sorry
great grandfather.
- [Crow] Well I've got
stuff in my pockets too.
Aha, insufferable.
- [Tom] Okay, now what?
- [Crow] Yeah, you wanna
live upriver of Crenshaw,
believe me.
- [Mike] Tim found a
hollow spot in a tree
and slept there.
- [Crow] Sunday
Times ever show up?
- [Mike] I rolled over on your
rat last night, I'm sorry.
- [Crow] Tim was
playing with these
you should really lock these up.
- [Mike] Within 45
seconds he kills everyone.
- Oh boy.
- Or old man whatever.
- You're right about one thing.
- [Tom] That was an
unnatural swelling.
- How's that?
- That thing oughta
be left alone.
- [Mike] I won't
touch it anymore.
To remain free and
live in the wild.
- [Crow] God bless
you half man half pig.
- [Brian] Crenshaw was not
telling me anything new.
For the last few days, I knew
this was the way it had to be.
Looks like I'm gonna fall
into the same category
as other people have done in
this area for years and years.
- [Tom] Ken Starr witness.
- [Brian] I just felt
for some special reason
what I saw and what I now know
I wanted to keep to myself.
There wasn't really a
matter of whether anyone
would believe me or not.
I guess it was a matter
of keeping him a mystery.
'Cause this is where he belongs.
It's like the old gentlemen
in the store said to me,
"Boy, there ain't no
monsters around here."
And you know something
they were right.
He's a part of nature
living in harmony
in one of America's
last great wildernesses.
- [Crow] Crenshaw,
that is right.
- [Brian] This
legend will continue
for I feel God
intended it that way.
- [Crow] So the once great
monster studies department
went under. (slow music)
Tanya and Leslie brought
me up on charges of course.
Tim just wondered off and we
haven't seen him in years.
- [Tom] You know what this
hairy guy put me in a room
and he gave me bacon to eat
'cause that's all he had
and then.
- I know, I know,
I'm sorry son.
- [Crow] And dad I
just had to sleep on hay
and the hay got all
messed up in my hair
and then the big guys smelled.
- [Mike] And then a bunch
of other people came in
and they were nice
except one of them wasn't
and there was this real
skinny kid with no shirt
and then this girl
screamed a lot.
- [Tom] I know I know, I know.
- [Crow] Hey,
mad dog provided by.
Mikey told me there was no
place we could get a mad dog.
(humming)
♪ A song from above on
the wings of a dove ♪
♪ Wings of a dove ♪
- [Mike] And you know what
there was a big blue reindeer
and he was nice to me and
he gave me all the presents
in the world.
- Really Bobby.
- [Mike] Yeah, his
name was snow head
and he lived in a big house
with a million other reindeer
where they ate cookies.
- [Crow] Uh-huh, what
kind of cookies, honey?
- [Mike] Chocolate.
- [Crow] Yeah every
movie from the south
is gonna thank a trailer
service at some point.
♪ From above on the
wings of a dove ♪
♪ Wings of a dove ♪
- [Mike] Goodnight,
Tim, wherever you are.
(doors close)
- Lord have mercy, I've
got to tend to my fires.
Oh hey cousin.
- Hi Croooow.
Hey permit me to ask what
may be a stupid question.
- You go right ahead boy.
- Why are you yet again
setting fires to the bridge.
- Well, you've finally
caught on old man.
I've got me a baby critter
and I'm trying to keep
his big old mama critter
away so you can patch him up.
- Ah, you go you a baby what?
- Hey I'm getting board lining
the straw in there Croooow,
I don't wanna play captive
baby Boggy Creek creature
and big smelly
mountian man anymore.
- Yeah, I'm kinda
tired of it too.
Hey let's go play
wounded baby unicorn
and skinny sociopathic janitor.
- Hooray!
(laughs)
- Hey guys can you
put out the fire first
before you get the
oh Pearl's calling.
It's really rather big
could you (blows flames).
Guys I need a hand.
- Hello Nelslob and
welcome to our legend
of forest or swamp
tourist gift shop.
Oh our first customer.
- Hello and welcome
to everything's legend
of forest or swamp, how may
I help you young moppet?
- My mama thinks she saw
him in the swamp once
mister white guy.
I saved up so as I can get
her something for her birthday
to remember that.
- Brain Guy, go do the
shelving and the stock room.
- But I need the commission.
- Scram.
Well, small person, did
you know that scientists
calculate the creatures
believability rating
as quite high.
- Wow.
- Yes,
but sadly no one has ever
had a face to face encounter
with one of these
mythological beasts.
- Mother, can I
get out of my room,
it's boring being a legend.
- Hey, he's just
a talking gorilla.
What's the big deal
about a talking gorilla?
- Not really.
- You're a bad lady, you
tried to trick my mommy.
(hollers)
And you're a stupid legend.
- Oh yeah well so are you kid!
I'm really addicted to
that little brat, huh?
Hey, hey, it's funny seeing
you for a change (indistinct).
I tell you nothing hurts
quite like getting kicked
to the ankle does it?
(Pearl punches gorilla)
(gorilla hollers)
(dramatic music)
- I saw the little creature.
- No, no.